Teiko Middle School
（ナレーション）
帝光(ていこう)中学 バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
その輝かしい歴史の中でも—
Even amidst their brilliant record,
there was a generation of five prodigies
known as the "Generation of Miracles."
10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた“キセキの世代”
黄瀬(きせ)涼太(りょうた)
Kise Ryota.
緑間(みどりま)真太郎(しんたろう)
Midorima Shintaro.
青峰(あおみね)大輝(だいき)
Aomine Daiki.
Murasakibara Atsushi.
紫原 敦(むらさきばらあつし)
Akashi Seijuro.
赤司征十郎(あかしせいじゅうろう)
そして
彼らを脅かす誠凛(せいりん)高校の—
They are threatened by Seirin High's
shadow and light.
影と光
（観客１）決まった！
He made the shot!
（観客２）エース対決は
火神(かがみ)が完全に押してる
Kagami's crushing Kise in the ace battle!
（黄瀬）こいつにだけは
絶対 負けたくない！
I don't want to lose to him!
Player substitution, black!
（オフィシャル）
メンバーチェンジ 黒
（武内(たけうち)）黄瀬 交代だ
Kise, you're out.
（火神）えいっ
（小堀(こぼり)）なっ…
He made it!
（観客）決まった！
（森山(もりやま)）でえっ
（火神）うっ
（小金井）行けー
Go!
What? A pass?
なっ パス!?
（木吉(きよし)）おおっ
（観客１）
ここで第２クオーター終了
The second quarter is over!
（観客２）同点だあ！
Kaijo
Seirin
We're tied!
There's no good way for us to
handle all five Seirin players.
（笠松(かさまつ)）今 誠凛５人に
もれなく対応できる—
都合のいい策はねえ
But we can still score.
だが 点は取れる
Stick to them like your life depends on it!
死んでも食らいつくぞ！
Yeah!
（海常(かいじょう)選手たち）おお！
（黒子(くろこ)）あっ…
A step back?
（日向(ひゅうが)）バックステップ!?
丸見えだぜ
You're in plain sight.
（観客１）止めたー！
He stopped it!
First it was Kise, now it's Kasamatsu!
（観客２）黄瀬に続いて笠松も！
We're not finished yet!
まだまだあ
海常 ナメんじゃねぇ！！
Don't underestimate Kaijo!
In Order to Win
We play Kaijo tomorrow.
（リコ）
明日はついに海常との決戦よ
We've beaten them before,
but don't let your guard down.
一度戦って勝ってる相手だけど
油断はしないで
Hey, Coach.
（日向）あー… カントク
オレたちが海常とやるのは
初めてだよ
This is our first time playing Kaijo.
What?
What are you talking about, Hyuga?
（小金井(こがねい)）何言ってんだよ 日向
まさか忘れちゃったの？
Did you forget?
You mean it's our first official game.
（伊月(いづき)）
公式戦では ってことか？
Yeah.
When we saw the Kaijo-Touou game
夏合宿の後 インターハイの
海常 桐皇(とうおう)戦 見に行ったとき—
during the Inter-High
after our summer training camp,
I overheard someone talking.
聞いちまったんだ
（生徒）ああ 誠凛ね 知ってる
Seirin? I know them.
でも練習試合で勝ったっつっても
インターハイには出てないんだろ？
They may have won a practice game,
but they're not in the Inter-High, right?
やっぱ結局
海常のほうが強いんじゃん？
Kaijo must be stronger.
（日向）世間の評価のために
バスケをしてるわけじゃない
We're not playing for praise.
それでもオレは
単純にそのとおりだと思った
But I knew they were right.
We played and won a practice game.
オレたちがやって勝ったのは
あくまで練習試合なんだ
Practice is preparation for the real game.
練習は本番のために
するもんだろ？
練習で100度 勝とうが
本番で負けたら何の意味もないんだ
You can win a hundred practice games,
but it's meaningless if you
can't win the real game.
（日向）しまっ…
Crap!
（森山）だあっ！
（日向）うおおおおおおー！
（早川(はやかわ)）うおおおおおおー！
うんがぁ！
（火神）こいつ 外れたボールへの
嗅覚がすげぇ！
He's got a keen eye for missed shots!
オフェンスリバウンドの
反応は特にだ
His reaction to offensive
rebounds is especially quick!
And No. 9 is putting all his effort
（伊月）しかも あの９番
スクリーンアウトに徹して—
into screening out Kagami
to keep him from jumping.
火神を飛ばせないことに
全力を注いでいる
Their teamwork is incredible.
なんて連係…
（小堀）早川！
（早川）んっ
Hayakawa!
うおぉぉっ！
（木吉）でやっ！
（小堀）ううっ！
Defense, pushing!
（審判）ディフェンス！
プッシング 白７番！
White No. 7!
Kaijo
Seirin
Basket counts!
バスケットカウント ワンスロー！
One free throw!
（小堀）っしゃぁ！
（森山）いいぞ小堀！
Yeah!
Nice work, Kobori!
（木吉）しまった…
Crap.
くそっ
Damn it.
Kiyoshi Teppei...
（小堀）木吉鉄平(てっぺい)
（木吉）んっ
君はオレより
ずっと優れたプレーヤーだ
You're much better than me.
けど オレは負けない…
But I won't lose.
Because we want to win more than you.
なぜなら オレたちのほうが
ずっと強く勝ちたいと思っている
We're more determined.
思いの強さが違う…
This is our chance for revenge.
オレたちにとって
この試合はリベンジマッチ
オマエたちは一度勝って
それを受ける側だ
Since you beat us once,
you're on the receiving end.
ましてや
君は以前の試合にはいなかった
And you weren't in the last game.
I won't lose to a guy who just wants to win.
ただ勝ちたいだけのヤツに
負けるものか！
（日向）
なんか言い返せよ ダアホ！
Say something, you moron!
（木吉）いってえ！
Ow!
Don't just listen to him speak his mind!
言いたい放題言われたあげく
黙りこんでんじゃねぇ！
いや あんまりに
もっともだと思ったんで ついな
It seemed reasonable, so I couldn't help it.
What?
（木吉）強いわけだと思ってさ
It explains why they're strong.
（日向）くっ… ゆうべのこと
もう忘れたんか…
Have you already forgotten last night?
You couldn't help it?!
Don't accept his logic, Iron Heart!
ついじゃねぇだろ
認めてどーすんだ
（日向）“鉄心”さんよぉ
（木吉）う…
あー すまんすまん
だから その呼び方やめて
Sorry.
So don't call me that.
（日向）だいたいここまで
ロクな活躍してねーじゃねぇか
You've hardly done anything until now!
頼むぜ“無冠の五将”！
We're counting on you, Uncrowned King!
いや それもやめろって
Don't call me that, either.
Where's the spirit you had when you
faced Murasakibara, Iron Heart?
紫原とやったときの気合いは
どこいったんだよ“鉄心”！
（木吉）嫌なんだって ホント！
I really don't like it.
しゃきっとしてくれよ“鉄心”！
Pull yourself together, Iron Heart!
（木吉）やめろって…
（日向）てーっしん！
Stop that.
Iron Heart, Iron Heart, Iron Heart...
てーっしん！ てーっしん！
てーっしん！
Iron Heart...
I told you to stop!
言ってるだろ さっきから！
いくら日向でも怒るぞ！
We may be friends, but you
don't get a free pass!
“鉄心”って言うな！
Don't call me Iron Heart!
Don't you know it takes one to know one?!
“鉄心”って言うヤツが
“鉄心”なんだぞ！
何言ってんだ！ 意味分かんねーよ
ダアホー！
What are you talking about?
That doesn't make any sense, idiot!
（木吉）日向だって
スリーぽこぽこ決められてんだろ！
Well, you've let tons of threes through!
（日向）うっせー！
オレはこれからなんじゃ バーカ！
Shut up! I'm just getting started!
Shouldn't we stop them?
（火神）い いいんスか あれ…
（日向）
鉄の心 アイアンハート
（伊月）
ほっとけ じきにおさまるから
Leave them.
（木吉）
日向のジョークより—
They'll stop eventually.
（伊月）
ほっとけ じきにおさまるから
伊月のほうが
ずっと面白いし！
（日向）はー！ 伊月より
つまんねえとか—
I'd rather die than make
lamer jokes than Izuki!
死んだほうがマシだ！ ダアホ！
Kaijo
Seirin
Come on!
（伊月）ドンマイ！ １本返すぞ！
Let's get them back!
（日向）くう…
ちょっ… マジで大丈夫なんスか？
Are they going to be okay?
They'll be fine.
だーいじょうぶだって
自分のプレーに集中しろよ
Focus on your own play.
It happens all the time.
別に珍しいことじゃねーから
What?
They've grown up since
you first-years joined.
（伊月）オマエら１年が入ってから
少し大人になったけど…
去年一緒にやってた頃は
しょっちゅうあんな感じだったよ
But when they played together last year,
they were like that all the time.
（火神）いや それダメじゃ…
Isn't that really bad?
よく言うだろ ケンカするほど
仲がいいって
They say the closer you
are, the more you fight.
They're the pillars that carried
the brand new Seirin team
なんだかんだで
できたばかりの誠凛を—
決勝リーグまで連れてった
２本柱だ
to the championship league.
頼りにしていいぜ
You can count on them.
I haven't forgotten.
（木吉）忘れたわけじゃないぞ
This is our only chance.
（木吉）今しかないんだ
このメンバーでプレーできるのは
今しか！
This is our only chance to
play with these members.
（中村(なかむら)）ええいっ！
No you don't!
（中村）させるか！
（水戸部(みとべ)）くっ…
I know, Hyuga.
（木吉）うぉぉぉぉぉ！
（木吉）分かってるよ 日向
オレたちが海常と戦うのは
初めてだ！
This is our first battle against Kaijo.
（日吉）うぉぉぉぉぉ！
（日吉）受ける側なんて思ってない！
We're not on the receiving end of anything!
Yes!
（小金井）よっしゃ〜！
（土田(つちだ)）押しこんだあ！
They pushed it through!
We've played before, but they're
not here for revenge against us.
（日向）因縁はあっても リベンジ
される側だなんて思ってない
If anything, it's the other way around.
むしろ逆！
オレたちは
夏 約束を果たせなかった
We failed to keep our promise last summer.
（森山）こいつ タイミングが
合ってきて…
He's starting to match my timing!
（日向）そのリベンジのために
ここにいる！
We're here to try again!
（森山）でいっ！
（日向）ううっ！
To beat Kaijo!
（日向）海常に勝つために！
（小金井）止めた〜！
He stopped it!
森山の変速シュートをブロック！
He stopped Moriyama's irregular shot!
ナイス 日向！
Nice, Hyuga!
（小金井）こっから反撃だあ〜！
It's time to strike back!
（木吉）むう…
（木吉）うぉぉっ！
（笠松）スクリーンから外 中かよ
A screen to the outside and back in?
（小金井）決まったあ〜！
He made it!
Nice pass.
ナイスパスだけど
スクリーンは よかったけど
Nice screen.
See?
息は合ってる…
They're on the same page...
They're strong.
（氷室(ひむろ)）強い…
（氷室）海常の気迫は
鬼気迫るものがある
Kaijo's intensity is monstrous.
（森山）うおぉぉぉ！
だが 誠凛のそれも
決して負けてはいない
But Seirin's is just as strong.
だあっ！
Coach, put me in!
監督！ やっぱりオレを…
くうっ…
（伊月）行け！ 火神！
（火神）うぉぉぉ！
Go, Kagami!
だあっ！
（ホイッスル）
よっしゃ〜！
Yes!
（根武谷(ねぶや)）おいおい もう
第４クオーターだよ 誠凛 海常戦
The Seirin-Kaijo game's already
entering its fourth quarter.
試合後のミーティング長かったなー
Our after-game meeting was long.
（実渕(みぶち)）しょーがないでしょ
We couldn't help it.
反省点の多い試合だったんだから
We had a lot to reflect on.
Who's going to win?
（葉山(はやま)）どっちが
勝ち上がってくるかなー？
どっちでも わくわくするなー
I'd be excited to play either one!
（赤司）試合経過は？
How's the game going?
（洛山(らくざん)部員）
第３クオーター終盤から—
Since the start of the third quarter,
誠凛ペースでリードを保っています
Seirin's held a lead and
maintained control of the game.
（観客１）お おい！ あれ…
H-Hey, isn't that...
（観客２）あ？ うぉ やっぱ強そー
They look so strong.
一足早く
ファイナル進出を決めた—
The first finalists,
and strongest school, Rakuzan High!
高校最強 洛山高校
そして１年にしてそれを率いる
“キセキの世代”赤司征十郎！
And their first-year captain,
Akashi Seijuro of the Generation of Miracles!
（木吉）ぬうっ！
Kaijo
Seirin
Yeah!
（小金井）よーしっ 10点差！
We're ten points ahead!
We're in control of the fourth quarter, too.
第４クオーターも流れはこっちだ
That's impressive.
（根武谷）おうおう すんげーな
あのダブルチームをぶち抜くかい
He broke through that double-team.
（実渕）
そこからパスを出してフィニッシュ
Then he passed to finish the play.
シンプルだけどキレイだわ
It's simple but beautiful.
（葉山）今のワンプレーでも
分かるよ 強(つえ)ぇー 誠凛！
I can tell from that one play!
Seirin's amazing!
赤司 どう思う？
Akashi, what do you think?
そうだね
Well, I can see how they
made it to the semi-finals.
準決勝まで残ってきたのも
うなずける
とてもできて２年目の
チームとは思えない
They play well.
They don't look like a
team in its second year.
海常もいいチームだが やはり
涼太抜きでは手に負えないだろう
Kaijo's a good team, but they
can't handle them without Ryota.
先遣隊の報告では 涼太は負傷交代
According to our scouts,
Ryota was subbed out for an injury.
Until then, he used his new
ability for about three minutes.
その前におよそ３分間
例の新技を使用したと聞いている
両チームの戦力差をふまえ
そして—
Considering their abilities as well as the fact
that Ryota has only two more
minutes to use his ability...
涼太の新技の使用限度が
残り２分だとすれば…
If we can pull 15 points ahead, we'll win.
15点差つければ ウチの勝ちよ
もちろん 絶対という話ではないわ
Naturally, it's not guaranteed.
But with 15 points, even with
his unstoppable Perfect Copy,
けれど 15点差あれば—
無敵のパーフェクトコピーでも
２分間の逆転は まず不可能
they can't make a comeback in two minutes.
最後まで逃げ切れる可能性が
一気に高くなる
Kaijo
Seirin
It will dramatically improve
our chances of winning.
With five more points, it's checkmate.
あと５点で チェックメイトよ
Coach.
（黒子）カントク
（リコ）ん…
（中村）ういっ！
リバン！
Rebound!
（小堀）だあっ！
He pushed it in!
（観客１）押し込んだー！
（観客２）海常もねばるー！
Kaijo's not giving up!
負けるか！
死んでもこれ以上 離されんな！
We won't lose!
Don't let them pull any farther ahead!
勝つ！ 何が何でも突き放すぞ！
We'll win!
Do everything it takes to pull ahead!
耐えろ… 耐えるんだ…
Be patient.
Be patient!
（黄瀬）頼む！
Please!
頑張れ… 頑張れ みんな！
Do your best!
Do your best, guys!
早川先輩
Hayakawa-senpai...
Moriyama-senpai...
森山先輩
Kobori-senpai...
小堀先輩
Nakamura-senpai...
中村先輩
笠松先輩！
Kasamatsu-senpai!
What?
The Inter-High game against Touou...
（黄瀬）インターハイの桐皇戦…
負けたのは オレのせいっス…
It's my fault we lost.
すんませんでした…
I'm sorry.
What are you talking about, idiot?
（笠松）バーカ 何言ってんだ
（黄瀬）え？
You're our ace.
（笠松）
オマエはウチのエースだろ？
Have they ever said anything like that?
あいつらが試合後
一度でもそんなこと言ったか？
（笠松）チームを勝たせるのが
エースの仕事だ
Leading his team to victory is the ace's job.
けど 負けたときの責任まで負うな
But you're not responsible for losses.
それはオレの仕事だ
That's my job.
エースは前だけ見てりゃいい
An ace just needs to face forward.
I...
（黄瀬）オレは…
（伊月）でやあっ！
（観客１）おー アリウープ！
（観客２）15点差ー！
An alley-oop!
They're 15 points ahead!
（観客３）海常 絶対絶命！
Kaijo is screwed!
くっ… くうっ…
Kise, wait! It's too soon!
（武内）黄瀬待て！ まだ早い！
（黄瀬）嫌っス オレは出る！
I don't care. I'm going in.
We still have four minutes.
（武内）まだ４分ある
If you push yourself for over
two minutes on that leg,
今のオマエの足で
２分以上 無茶したら—
後々まで影響が出る可能性が…
you could suffer long-term effects.
（黄瀬）監督
Coach,
the ace's job is to lead his team to victory.
エースは チームを勝たせるのが
仕事っスよね
今 行かなきゃエースじゃない！
If I don't play now, I'm not the ace!
もし行かなかったら 絶対後悔する
If I don't go, I'll regret it.
After all...
だって…
オレ このチーム… 好きなんスもん
I love this team.
分かった
Fine.
（黄瀬）あ…
（武内）ただし—
But if I think you're in
danger, I'm subbing you out.
少しでも危ないと
ワシが判断したら—
すぐ交代させるぞ
了解っス
Roger that.
交代ヨロシク
I'm subbing in.
交代 お願いします
Coach.
（小金井）カントク
（リコ）あ…
黒子を出すの まだ早くない？
Isn't it too soon to sub Kuroko in?
He still can't use his Phantom Shot.
ファントムシュートも
破られたままだしな
His Misdirection is pretty
weak against Kaijo right now.
（小金井）
海常にミスディレクションは—
もうかなり弱まってるんでしょ？
私もそう思ったんだけど…
I thought so, too.
15点差もあるわ
We have a 15 point lead.
We can wait and see.
（リコ）もう少し様子を見ても…
（黒子）だからです
That's why I have to play.
黄瀬君に勝つために
To beat Kise-kun.
Nothing's scarier than when he's cornered.
追い詰められた彼らほど
怖いものはありません
（リコ）“キセキの世代”の怖さを
黒子君が一番分かっている
Kuroko knows the terror of the
Generation of Miracles better than any of us.
だから頼んだわよ 黒子君…
So we're counting on you, Kuroko-kun.
I've steeled my resolve.
（武内）ワシは腹をくくったぞ
最後までやれ
See this through.
You're Kaijo's ace, Kise.
海常のエースはオマエだ 黄瀬！
The final four minutes.
（リコ）ラスト４分…
Go get 'em!
（リコ・武内）行ってこい！
Ow! Don't push me, Satsuki!
（青峰）あいてっ
（青峰）押すなって さつき！
（さつき）早く！
Hurry up! We're going to miss the game!
試合終わっちゃう！
（青峰）見に行かなくて
いいっつってたろ オマエ
You said we didn't have to come.
（さつき）ん〜 気が変わったの！
I changed my mind.
I need to see with my own
eyes how this game ends.
やっぱり この試合の結果は
自分の目で見ないとって！
Ouch...
あっ いてえって！
（青峰）よかったな さつき
（さつき）え？
You got lucky, Satsuki.
Huh?
（青峰）
どうやら役者が揃ったとこらしいぜ
Looks like all the players are here.
It's the climax.
クライマックスだ
ハア…
（赤司）
海常はギリギリだったようだな
Kaijo was barely hanging on.
もう少し遅ければ
精神的に折れていたかもしれない
If they'd waited any longer, it
may have broken their spirits.
それだけでも 涼太投入は正解だ
For that reason alone, subbing
in Ryota was the right choice.
（氷室）
だが 残り時間４分に対して—
But there are four minutes
left in the game to his
パーフェクトコピーが
使えるのは２分
two minutes of Perfect Copy.
仮にミスなく使い切ったとしても…
Even if he makes no mistakes...
この点差だ… 追いつけるもんか！
We're so far ahead.
They can't catch up.
We definitely have Kaijo on the ropes.
（リコ）今の状況…—
はっきり言って ウチが海常を
追い詰めてるのは間違いないわ
けど… この胸騒ぎは何!?
But...
Why do I feel so uneasy?
Hey.
よう… やっと出てきたな
You're finally here.
I've been waiting for...
待って… た…
（黒子）火神君
Kagami-kun.
（火神）ああ どうやら一瞬も
気は抜けなそーだ
Yeah.
We can't let out guard down.
（黒子）はい
Yes.
ボクもそう思います
I agree.
試合終了のブザーが鳴るまで—
Until we hear the end of game buzzer,
勝負は何が起こるか分かりません
there's no telling what will happen.
（日向）最後まで気を抜くな！
ハンズアップ！ 声出せ！
Don't relax until it's over!
Hands up!
Let me hear you!
Yeah!
（笠松）チィッ
Hey!
ヘイ！
He's here!
（観客）
きたーっ 海常エース 黄瀬！
Kaijo's ace, Kise!
（黄瀬）そう エースはオレだ…
That's right. I'm the ace.
The ace leads his team to victory.
そして
チームを勝たせるのがエース
もう二度と負けたくない
I don't want to lose again.
負けさせたくない
I won't let them lose again.
I will lead Kaijo to victory.
オレが海常を勝たせる
（火神）まさか…
Could it be?
（黄瀬）誠凛に…
We'll beat
Seirin!
勝つんだ！
（火神）赤司のエンペラーアイで
切り返し—
He crossed over from Akashi's
Emperor Eye into Aomine's drive!
青峰の超速ドライブ これは…
This is
Perfect Copy!
パーフェクトコピー！
（歓声）
（武内）よぉし！
Yes!
そんな…
But...
He's unbelievable.
（火神）
相変わらず とんでもねえヤツだ…
が オマエなら なんとなく
そんな気もしてたぜ…
But,
I had a feeling you'd do this!
That's why
だから—
this isn't enough to make me back down!
こんぐらいで ひるむかよ！
Kagami-kun!
火神君！
（黒子）でいっ！
（火神）くっ！
Counterattack!
（土田）カウンター！
What?
（森山）何っ！
And...
（小金井）しかも…
（火神）うぉぉぉ！
（小金井）レーンアップ！
It's a layup!
（伊月）青峰のアジリティ プラス
紫原のブロック
Aomine's agility plus Murasakibara's blocks!
黒子から火神のカウンターを
止めるなんて！
I can't believe he stopped Kuroko
and Kagami's counterattack!
はっ！ まずい 戻れ！
This isn't good! Head back!
Wha—
You're kidding!
（リコ）ウソでしょ！？
（黄瀬）でぇいっ！
He copied Tetsu-kun's pass!
テツ君のパスをコピーした!?
（小堀）ふんっ！
ハアッ… ぬうっ！
Kaijo
Seirin
Nice shot, Kobori-san!
（早川）ナイスえす こぼさん！
（小堀）ああ！
Yeah!
We'll win!
勝つ！ ここから残り
オレのすべてを懸けて！
I'll put everything I have on the line!
The final spurt of a cornered member
of the Generation of Miracles...
（火神）土壇場の
“キセキの世代”の追い込み—
The pressure is incredible!
なんつープレッシャーだよ
まさか… 黒子のパスまで
コピーするなんて…
I can't believe he copied Kuroko's pass.
（日向）どこまで進化すんだよ
この化け物は！
How much can this monster evolve?
けど 残り４分の試合で
いきなり仕掛けてきた
But he's already using it
with four minutes left.
Is he using up everything now?
ここですべて出し切るつもりか？
No.
（リコ）いいえ…
（リコ）可能性はもう１つあるわ
（小金井）え？
There's another possibility.
What?
最後まで持たせるつもりか… よ
He'll make it last until the end.
パーフェクトコピーの代償である
激しい体力の消耗
Using Perfect Copy consumes a
tremendous amount of stamina.
それがなぜか
前半より少なくなってる
But for some reason it's burning
less now than in the first half.
このペースなら持つかもしれない…
At this rate, it may last.
It puts a comeback well within their reach.
そうなったら
逆転は十分に可能だわ
We were naive to think we could stay ahead.
逃げ切るなんて 考えが甘かった
やはりこの戦い—
We can't win
パーフェクトコピーを
止めなければ勝てない！
without stopping his Perfect Copy.
Preview
（日向）ちくしょう！
Damn it!
His Perfect Copy put them
in control of the game!
パーフェクトコピーに完全に
流れを持ってかれたぜ！
（伊月）声援も みんな海常に…
観客まで敵になったみたいだ
They're all cheering for Kaijo.
The fans are against us, too.
Focus!
（日向）集中しろ！
こっからは絶対ミスはできねえぞ！
We can't afford any mistakes!
This Time
（伊月）ああ 絶対勝つぞ！
Yeah.
We will win!